A Guide to the College of Education Restructuring Records, 1979-1996
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- E-mail - Tom Sherman to COE faculty: "Message for faculty" (RIF policy) Oct 1995 (Box-folder 1-105)
- Personnel resource allocation matrix c. 1995 (Box-folder 3-106)
- Dianne W. Robertshaw and Larry Harris - "Restructuring a College of Education to Meet Contemporary Public School Needs" n.d. (Box-folder 3-107)
- Racial equality 1994-1995 (Box-folder 1-108)
  - Breakdown of advanced degrees by race - COE vs. university
- Interviews with College of Education faculty 1995 (Box-folder 3-109)
- Dismantling the College of Education 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3-110-110a)
  - Memo from Worner to Torgersen - "Argument against decision"
  - Memo from Torgersen to COE faculty and staff announcing merger
  - Agenda of COE Executive Committee meeting
  - Sherman announcing Faculty Senate meeting with Torgersen
  - Roanoke Times article - "College merger a tough lesson"
  - Roanoke Times article - "Faculty protest merger"
  - Faculty Senate resolution
  - E-mail from Worner - "College of Education status"
  - Newspaper article (Roanoke Times?) "Discontent at Virginia Tech: campus upset about education college merger"
  - Worner e-mail - "Meeting with superintendents and Spectrum article"
  - Worner e-mail - "Communication"
  - Spectrum article - "President outlines changes for College of Education"
  - Photocopy of Spectrum article - "Torgersen answers staff questions"
  - Minutes of November Staff Senate meeting
  - "Myths and 'myth-information' surrounding the decision to close the College of Education at Virginia Tech" (written by Worner; distribution, if any, unclear)
  - "Restructuring at Virginia Tech: a (Grim) Fairy Tale" (by Worner; distribution, if any, unclear)
  - Agenda and Worner's summary of all-day meeting on merger
  - Letter from Torgersen attached to letter from Meszaros to Torgersen recommending merger
  - Letter from Pat Edwards (chair) to "faculty, staff participants in interviews for the Dean of Human Resources and Education" - list of finalists, short vitas attached
  - E-mail from Emily Oliver (dean's office) - "Merger planning activities"
- Transcript - Torgersen at College of Education faculty meeting Nov 15 1995 (Box-folder 3-111)
- Transcript of Torgersen at Staff Senate meeting Nov 16 1995 (Box-folder 3-112)
  - Transcript
  - Minutes
- Torgersen interviewed by C. Pinson Dec 1995 (Box-folder 3-113)
- Restructuring in Arts and Sciences 1995 (Box-folder 3-114)
- Dean Worner's presentation to the Board of Visitors 1995 (Box-folder 3-115)
- Meeting with provost on future of College of Education Dec 12 1995 (Box-folder 3-116)
- Second meeting with provost on future of College of Education Dec 14 1995 (Box-folder 3-117)
- Third meeting with provost on future of College of Education Dec 18 1995 (Box-folder 3-118-118a)
- Mobilizing protest against merger 1993-1996 (Box-folder 3-119-119b)
- Protest letters to Torgersen 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3-120-120a)
- Open letter to the Virginia Tech community Apr 23 1996 (Box-folder 3-121)
- Archive interviews, College of Education Dec 1994 (Box-folder 3-122)
  - VHS tape of interviews